[electricity crackling]
I'M SEEING LIGHTS. DEFINITELY
PEOPLE INSIDE THE HOUSE.HOW MANY ENTRY POINTS?
THREE--FRONT, BACK, BASEMENT.
WINDOWS ARE ALL BOARDED UP.WITNESSES SAID THREE MEN
TOOK PART IN THE ABDUCTION.
SO FIGURE THOSE THREE INSIDE
PLUS A COUPLE MORE JUST FOR FUN.
THIS IS MIA WESTLAKE.
I WANT EVERYBODY TO TAKE
ANOTHER GOOD, LONG LOOK.
WE HAVE EVERY REASON TO BELIEVE
THE KIDNAPPER'S GOT HER ALIVE
IN THERE, SO BE CAREFUL.
ME, HICKS AND MARTINEZ
TAKE THE FRONT DOOR.
DYSON AND SHELLY,
YOU TAKE THE TWO-THREE CORNER.
BUCCI, PAULSON AND FREDERICKS,
YOU TAKE THE THREE-FOUR.
LET'S GO.[guns cock]
[whispers] READY.
READY.
[lowers voice]
THREE, TWO, ONE.
STAY WHERE YOU ARE! FBI!
DOWN! GET DOWN![shouting indistinctly]
GET DOWN! GET DOWN![all shouting at once]
GET DOWN!
JANE?
LISBON?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?YOU'RE WAVING YOUR GUNS AROUND,
IS WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
CAN YOU JUST
PUT YOUR GUNS AWAY, PLEASE?
COWBOYS!
♪♪
SIR, THE IMPORTANT THING
IS NOBODY GOT HURT.
ALL RESPECT
TO YOUR PEOPLE, LISBON,
THE IMPORTANT THING IS
WE MAKE SURE
THAT THIS DOES NOT
HAPPEN AGAIN.
"CBI AGENTS SHOOT EACH OTHER"
IS NOT A HEADLINE
THAT I WANT TO SEE.
WE CAME IN HOT
BECAUSE WE THOUGHT
THE KIDNAP VICTIM WAS THERE.MIA SOMEBODY.
MIA WESTLAKE.
MARIN COUNTY HEIRESS.MIA WESTLAKE.
SHE WAS TAKEN
A DAY AND A HALF AGO.
WITNESS GAVE US A PARTIAL PLATE
ON THE KIDNAPPER'S CAR.
WE DUG UP AN OUTSTANDING
PARKING TICKET
TO A CAR IN OAKLAND,
CHECKED THE ADDRESS,
FOUND THERE WERE PEOPLE
INSIDE A HOUSE
THAT WAS SUPPOSED TO BE EMPTY.AND HE FOUND
YOU THERE BECAUSE?
WE GOT A CALL FROM
THE CORONER'S BUREAU.
THERE WAS A REPORT
OF A CORPSE IN A HOUSE.
BUT THEY WERE SHORTHANDED--
BUDGET CUTS--
SO THEY ASKED US
TO GO AND CHECK IT OUT.
MY TEAM WENT IN THE HOUSE.
THE CORPSE WAS THERE
BUT THE CORONER WASN'T,
SO WE WAITED.
AND EVERYONE ALMOST DIED
IN A HAIL OF BULLETS.
WHERE ARE YOU WITH WESTLAKE?
WE'RE SET UP
INSIDE THE HOUSE.
WE'RE WAITING
FOR A RANSOM DEMAND.
WHAT'S WITH THE CORPSE?A YOUNG MALE DEAD
THREE TO FIVE YEARS.
CORONER COULDN'T BE SPECIFIC.
THERE WERE TWO BULLET HOLES
IN THE BASE OF THE SKULL.
IT WAS WRAPPED IN PLASTIC
AND STORED IN A WINDOW SEAT.DO YOU HAVE AN I.D.?
NOT YET.YES YET.
CORONER'S REPORT JUST CAME IN,
AND THE CORPSE IS...
COLIN HAYMER.
HAYMER? WHY DO I
RECOGNIZE THAT NAME?
COLIN HAYMER WAS A KIDNAP VICTIM
THREE YEARS AGO.
EARLY 20s FROM SAN FRANCISCO,
WEALTHY FAMILY.
S.F.P.D. HANDLED THE CASE.
FAMILY PAID THE RANSOM.THAT DIDN'T WORK.
EERILY SIMILAR TO YOUR
KIDNAPPING, DON'T YOU THINK?
WHO WANTS TO BET COLIN HAYMER'S
KIDNAPPER'S THE SAME KIDNAPPERS
THAT KIDNAPPED MIA WESTLAKE?WELL, COULD BE A COINCIDENCE.
THERE ARE NO COINCIDENCES.
I AGREE. I WANT YOUR PEOPLE
TEAMING UP ON THIS.
[sighs] IS THAT NECESSARY?I BELIEVE IT IS.
I WANT TO FOSTER BETTER
INTER-UNIT RELATIONS.
LET'S STOP STUMBLING INTO EACH
OTHER AND TRY WORKING TOGETHER.
YOU HAVE CONCERNS.
I DO.
THIS MAN IS A... A...
I-I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT HE IS.
HE'S AN ACCIDENT
WAITING TO HAPPEN.
SAM, BE FAIR. HE--CLOSES CASES, I KNOW.
I DO.HE DOES.
I DO.
IN MY OPINION,
THIS IS A MISTAKE.
WE'RE ALL AGREED THEN.
[sighs deeply]
OFF YOU GO.
MIA WESTLAKE WAS
ABDUCTED 38 HOURS AGO
COMING HOME
FROM A GALLERY OPENING.
THANK YOU, REBECCA.
UH, YOU NEED ANYTHING ELSE?NO, WE'RE GOOD. THANK YOU.
THIS IS COPIES
OF THE CASE PAPERWORK SO FAR.
NOW THE KIDNAPPERS FORCED
HER CAR OFF THE ROAD,
KILLED THE DRIVER
AND THEN TOOK HER.
WHY KILL THE DRIVER?
IT'S A MESSAGE. THEY WON'T
HESITATE TO KILL THE HOSTAGE
IF THEY DON'T GET
WHAT THEY WANT.YES.
THERE'S NO RANSOM DEMAND YET.
HOW DO WE KNOW
IT'S A KIDNAPPING?THEY SENT THE FAMILY A PROOF
OF LIFE A FEW HOURS LATER.
NO BLINDFOLD. THAT'S NOT GOOD.
MEANS THEY DON'T CARE
IF SHE SEES ANYTHING.GOOD THINKING, BERT.
WHAT'S YOUR PROBLEM?NO PROBLEM.
[Lisbon] HEY.RIGSBY'S CORRECT.
THIS IS SHAPING UP TO END
LIKE THE HAYMER ABDUCTION.
LET'S MAKE SURE
THAT IT DOESN'T.
ALL RIGHT, I GOTTA GET BACK
TO THE WESTLAKES'.I'D LIKE TO COME WITH
IF THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
I'D LIKE TO ASK
THE WESTLAKES SOME QUESTIONS
ABOUT OUR DEAD GUY,
SEE IF THERE'S ANY CONNECTION.[Bosco] OKAY.
START DIGGING
ON THE HAYMER CASE.
CONTACT THE FAMILY,
SET UP INTERVIEWS.AND I'D LIKE TO LEAVE HICKS
HERE TO WORK WITH YOUR TEAM.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT WITH YOU?
KEEP 'EM HONEST.[Lisbon] OKAY.
[Van Pelt] HEY.[Rigsby] WHAT DID HE SAY?
[Lisbon]
CARE TO REFRAME THAT, SAM?NO. THEY'RE JANE'S PEOPLE.
THEY NEED WATCHING.
I LIKE TO THINK OF THEM
AS MYPEOPLE.WELL, THINK WHAT YOU LIKE.
I CAN'T HAVE THEM TRYING TO PULL
SOME CHEAP STUNT BEHIND MY BACK.
WELL, WE HAVE A WHOLE RANGE
OF EXPENSIVE STUNTS
IF YOU DON'T LIKE
THE CHEAP ONES.I UNDERSTAND YOUR ISSUE,
AGENT BOSCO.
NO PROBLEM. WELCOME, HICKS.[Van Pelt] BOSS.
WE'LL EXTEND EVERY COURTESY.
LET'S GET STARTED,
SHALL WE?
[police radio chatter]
[Bosco] THIS IS VERONA WESTLAKE.
THIS IS MIA'S SISTER.
YOU MUST BE CBI, TOO?
I'M AGENT LISBON.
THAT'S PATRICK JANE.
HI.
UH, MY HUSBAND DUNCAN WEAVER.HEY.
MORE CBI?
WHERE DID YOU GUYS COME FROM,
ANYWAY?
TWO DAYS AGO,
I NEVER HEARD OF YOU.YOU NEITHER. NICE PLACE.
YOU GUYS MUST BE LOADED.
HOW DID YOU MAKE THE MONEY?
UH, MY GRANDFATHER, ACTUALLY--
OIL, LUMBER.
OH! I JUST ASSUMED
IT WAS NEW MONEY,
BECAUSE OF THE, UH,
THE DECOR.
[lowers voice] UM, ALREADY
YOU START WITH THIS CRAP?
[lowers voice] WHAT? WHAT?
UH, BELINDA SANDBORNE,
VERONA'S ATTORNEY.
ANY CONVERSATION YOU HAVE
WITH VERONA OR DUNCAN,
I NEED TO BE THERE.NOT A PROBLEM. IS THERE
SOMEONE ELSE IN THE FAMILY
WE SHOULD BE TALKING TO?
I'M SORT OF... THE FAMILY.
OUR PARENTS ARE DEAD.
[sniffles]
YOU KNOW, MIA--
SHE'S THE GROWN-UP, CAPABLE ONE.
I'M THE MESS.
HEY.
TOO BAD, HUH?
THEY TOOK THE WRONG SISTER.
YOU'RE DOING FINE.
LISTEN TO THE MAN
WITH THE GUN, BABE.
WE UNDERSTAND YOU'RE
INVESTIGATING A RELATED CASE?
ANOTHER KIDNAPPING
THAT MAY HAVE BEEN CARRIED OUT
BY THE SAME PEOPLE, YES.HOW DID IT, UM, TURN OUT?
DID THE--DID THE PERSON
THEY TOOK GET HOME OKAY?
NO. HE WAS KILLED.
HIS NAME IS COLIN HAYMER.
HERE'S HIS PICTURE.
HE'S FROM PACIFIC HEIGHTS.
DOES HE LOOK FAMILIAR?
NO. YOU, BABE?
NOTHING. SORRY.
DOES HIS NAME EVER COME UP
IN ANY CONTEXT, EVEN CASUALLY?
I DON'T THINK SO.
HE WAS WORKING AT A COMPANY
CALLED STRAF INVESTMENTS
WHEN HE WAS TAKEN. DO YOU HAVE
ANYTHING TO DO WITH THEM?
STRAF?
UM... BELINDA?
NO, I DON'T THINK SO.
I'LL CHECK THE RECORDS.
I'M SORRY I'M NOT REALLY
HELPING. I'M TRYING.
I'M--I'M NOT...
HELLO! OKAY. [chuckles]
LOOK WHAT I FOUND.OH, GOD.
UH, LEVI,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING IN HERE?
SHE'S YOURS?
YES. UH, MRS. KENT?
WHERE IS SHE?MRS. KENT!
OH, SHE'S FINE. UM...
[sniffs] SHE'S A LITTLE SMELLY,
BUT, UH, OTHER THAN THAT,
SHE'S A LITTLE CHERUB.
SORRY, SORRY.
MRS. KENT,
PLEASE KEEP HER IN HER ROOM.
WE DISCUSSED THIS.YES, MA'AM.
BOSS, RANSOM DEMAND
JUST CAME IN.
COME ON.
EXCUSE ME.SORRY.
[makes popping sound]
AH.
IT'S A VIDEO ATTACHMENT
TO AN E-MAIL.
CAN YOU GET THE I.P. ADDRESS?OH, I'M TRYING,
BUT THEY ROUTED IT
THROUGH A BUNCH OF SERVERS.
IT MIGHT TAKE DAYS. [speaks indistinctly]
[gasps]
YOU--YOU WANT ME
TO READ THIS?
OKAY.
"MY NAME IS MIA WESTLAKE.
I AM NOT HURT.
"I AM BEING TREATED WELL.
"FOR MY SAFE RETURN,
"YOU MUST PAY $3.75 MILLION
"IN SMALL, NONSEQUENTIAL BILLS.
"THIS MONEY IS TO BE READY
BY 6:00 P.M. TONIGHT.
"YOU WILL BE INSTRUCTED
WHAT TO DO THEN.
FAILURE TO COMPLY
WILL RESULT..."
"IN MY IMMEDIATE EXECUTION."
[crying]
"ANY INTERFERENCE WILL RESULT
IN MY IMMEDIATE EXECUTION."
VERONA, IF YOU'RE
WATCHING THIS, I...
DID YOU SEE THE TAT
ON THAT GUY?YEAH.
I MEAN, THAT LOOKS
LIKE MEXICAN MAFIA.MM.
WE'RE NOT GONNA GET ANYTHING
OUT OF THE WESTLAKES NOW.
LET'S GO.
$3.75 MILLION--VERY SPECIFIC
NUMBER, DON'T YOU THINK?
MAYBE THE KIDNAPPERS
HAVE THEIR EYE
ON THE WESTLAKES' BANK ACCOUNT.
I'LL TALK TO BOSCO ABOUT IT,
THEN WE'LL GO.
OKAY. TAKE YOUR TIME.
WH--HEY, EXCUSE ME.
UH, WE'D LIKE SOME PRIVACY.
I CAN UNDERSTAND THAT.
WHAT'S IN YOUR POCKET?
NONE OF YOUR BUSINESS.
YOU JUST KEEP TAPPING IT...
TAP, TAP, TAPPING IT.
WHATEVER IS IN THERE, YOU'RE
OBVIOUSLY NERVOUS ABOUT IT.
I'M ASSUMING IT'S ILLEGAL.[pouring liquid]
MY BEST GUESS WOULD BE...
DRUGS.
UH, DO--DO YOU HAVE
ANY LEMON?
I'M GONNA GO FIND
YOUR BOSS, ALL RIGHT?
OKAY. WELL, BE SURE
TO TELL HER ABOUT THE DRUGS
IN YOUR TOP POCKET.
IF YOU NEED ME,
I'M GONNA BE RIGHT HERE
TALKING TO YOUR LOVELY WIFE.
[voice breaking]
PLEASE LEAVE, ALL RIGHT?
I JUST WANT TO BE ALONE.THAT'S WHAT WE ALL WANT.
NO ONE GETS IT.
SO THERE'S NO LEMONS HERE?
NO, I DON'T THINK SO!
I REALLY FELT LIKE...
MM, NEVER MIND.
YOUR SISTER
NEEDS YOU HERE NOW.
AS COMFORTING AS IT MIGHT BE
TO CRAWL UNDER THE BLANKET
OF NARCOTICS THAT YOUR HUSBAND
HAS SO GENEROUSLY PROCURED
FOR YOU,
IT'S BETTER THAT YOU DON'T.
[sniffles] NOTHING I DO
IS GOING TO HELP HER.
YOU'RE PROBABLY RIGHT.
WHAT'S THE POINT?
WHAT YOU CAN ACCOMPLISH
IS IRRELEVANT.
BUT IF YOU ARE ABSENT
IN THIS MOMENT,
YOU WILL REGRET IT
FOR THE REST
OF WHAT WILL BE
A MISERABLE LIFE.
THAT'S ALL.
SEE YOU.
[Lisbon] WHAT WERE YOU
DOING BACK THERE?
OH, JUST GETTING A SNACK,
A LITTLE LIGHT REFRESHMENT.
WHY DON'T I BELIEVE YOU?WHAT? W-WHAT IS THIS?
THIS IS PROOF OF MY VERACITY.IT'S TIME TO GO.
I'M GONNA STAY.I KNOW WHAT THIS IS ABOUT.
BOSCO'S GOT THE RED JOHN FILE.
YOU THINK IF YOU HANG AROUND
LONG ENOUGH,
YOU'LL WEASEL YOUR WAY INTO IT."WEASEL" IS A LITTLE STRONG.
YOU'RE WASTING YOUR TIME.
BOSCO WILL NEVER GO FOR IT.
NEVER.
WHAT?
I'LL NEVER GO FOR WHAT?I LIKE THE WAY YOU WORK.
I WANT TO WORK ON YOUR TEAM
ON THE, UH, KIDNAPPING DETAIL.
OH, YOU DO, HUH?
A LIVE KIDNAPPING VICTIM
IS SO MUCH MORE MY SPEED
THAN A SHRIVELED CORPSE.LIKE I CARE ABOUT YOUR SPEED.
LISBON, YOU CLAIM TO HAVE
CONTROL OVER THIS WHACK-JOB.
WHY DON'T YOU DO ME A FAVOR
AND WALK HIM AWAY?DON'T TALK TO ME THAT WAY.
YEAH, THAT'S VERY RUDE.QUIET. MINELLI GAVE US
SPECIFIC ORDERS.
I DON'T GIVE A FLYING--HEY. HEY, HEY, HEY!
YOU THIS AGENT'S BOSS?
WHY?I WANT HIM REMOVED
FROM THIS CASE NOW.
NOW,ALL RIGHT?
HE'S--HE'S DISRESPECTFUL
AND, UH, RUDE
AND--AND UNPROFESSIONAL.OH, HE'S JUST ANGRY
'CAUSE I CALLED HIM
ON HIS LITTLE DRUG DEAL THING.OKAY, YOU'RE NUTS.
I HAVE NO DRUGS.
LIAR.
I DEMAND YOU TAKE
THIS MAN OFF THE CASE,
OR THERE WILL BE
SERIOUS CONSEQUENCES.WELL, SIR,
THAT'S NOT YOUR CALL.
OH, YEAH? YOU THINK?
ONE PHONE CALL, I CAN HAVE YOU
DIRECTING TRAFFIC.
IS THAT RIGHT?
YEAH, IT IS.
WELL, MAKE YOUR CALL, BECAUSE
THIS MAN'S STAYING ON THE CASE
WHETHER YOU LIKE IT OR NOT.REALLY?
YEAH.YOU SEE--SEE THIS? YOU SEE
WHAT HE'S DONE TO MY WIFE?
I MEAN,
THIS GUY'S OUT OF CONTROL.SHUT UP, DUNCAN.
BABY,
I WAS TRYING TO EXPLAIN--SHUT UP.
MR. JANE, IS IT?
YEAH.
WHAT YOU SAID EARLIER
WAS RIGHT. THANK YOU...
I GUESS. [chuckles]
[sniffles]
LEAVE HIM ALONE.
OKAY, THEN. IT'S SETTLED.
HAVE FUN. BOYS.
WAIT.
FROM THE COLIN HAYMER CASE.
SO YOU WANT NAMES THAT BEGIN
WITH "A" THROUGH "L"
OR "M" THROUGH "Z"?"A" THROUGH "L."
YOU GOT IT.
CHANGED MY MIND.
I WANT "M" THROUGH "Z."
TOO LATE. YOU ALREADY CHOSE.
OH, COME ON.
ROCK, PAPER, SCISSORS? STEP UP.
HEY, BERT, CAN I GET
ON THIS ROCK, PAPER, SCISSORS?
I HAVEN'T HAD A REALLY GOOD
GAME SINCE I WAS, OH, 10.
IT'S RIGSBY.
I KNOW.
HEY, WHAT'S WITH HICKS
CALLING ME BERT?
UM, I'M SURE I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S BERT, LIKE THE MUPPET.
IT'S JUST A STUPID NICKNAME.
IT DOESN'T MEAN ANYTHING.
BOSCO'S TEAM CALLS US
BERT AND ERNIE.
YOU KNEW THAT,
AND YOU DIDN'T SAY ANYTHING?IT WOULD BOTHER YOU.
IT DOESN'T BOTHER YOU?NO.
WHY NOT?ERNIE'S THE CLEVER,
HANDSOME ONE.
WHERE'S JANE?WITH BOSCO.
DON'T ASK ME WHAT THEY'RE DOING,
BECAUSE I DON'T KNOW
AND I DON'T CARE.
WHAT DO YOU GOT?I'VE BEEN CHECKING OUT
THE HOUSE
WHERE WE FOUND
COLIN HAYMER'S BODY.
IT'S BEEN ABANDONED
SEVEN YEARS.
THERE WERE SOME COMPLAINTS
ABOUT SQUATTERS
FIVE, SIX YEARS AGO.
NOTHING ELSE.
AGENT LISBON,
THERE'S A LOUIS EARLEN
TO SEE YOU IN YOUR OFFICE.KEEP DIGGING.
RIGHT.
LIEUTENANT EARLEN.
THANKS FOR COMING.LOUIS, PLEASE. I'M RETIRED.
SO YOU FOUND
POOR COLIN HAYMER?
WE DID.
YOU WERE THE S.F.P.D. OFFICER
IN CHARGE OF THE KIDNAPPING
INVESTIGATION, RIGHT?
I WAS. SPENT A LOT OF TIME
WITH THE HAYMER FAMILY.
HAVE THEY BEEN NOTIFIED?THEY HAVE.
OH. HOPE IT'S SOME KIND
OF CONSOLATION.
THEY'VE BEEN WAITING
A LONG TIME FOR THAT BOY.
WE HAVE ANOTHER KIDNAPPING.
WE THINK THE SAME PEOPLE
MIGHT BE BEHIND IT.
HOW CAN I HELP?
ANYBODY YOU THINK
WE SHOULD TAKE A LOOK AT?
[chuckles] TALL ORDER.
WE LOOKED AT A LOT OF PEOPLE.
WELL, WE WERE WONDERING
IF MAYBE IT WAS AN INSIDE JOB.
THE RANSOM DEMAND
WAS PRETTY SPECIFIC.
WE CONSIDERED THAT.
I ALWAYS HAD A FEELING
ABOUT COLIN'S GIRLFRIEND--
NOTHING SOLID, JUST A FEELING.DO YOU REMEMBER HER NAME?
DIANE ZAR... ZARANSKI.
YEAH.
TALKED TO HER
A COUPLE OF TIMES.
WHEN'S THE RANSOM DROP?
TONIGHT, 6:00.UH-HUH.
THE NIGHT COLIN'S RANSOM
GOT PAID,
I SAT WITH HIS PARENTS
TILL MORNING
JUST WAITIN' TO HEAR
HE WAS SAFE.
DON'T THINK WE SAID
TEN WORDS.
[sighs]
IF IT IS THE SAME PEOPLE
THAT TOOK COLIN,
YOU DO THIS GIRL'S FAMILY
A FAVOR.
MONEY DROPS AT 6:00.
AT 6:01, YOU TELL THEM
THEIR CHILD IS DEAD,
GIVE 'EM A CHANCE
TO GET USED TO IT.
IT WOULD BE A KINDNESS.
BOSS, I MIGHT HAVE SOMETHING.WHAT?
THOSE SQUATTERS IN THE HOUSE
WHERE WE FOUND HAYMER?
THEY WERE DRUG DEALERS.
A DETECTIVE IN OAKLAND NARCOTICS
SAID THEY'RE AN EXTENDED
FAMILY--EIGHT OR TEN PEOPLE.
THEY GREW POT ON A FARM
CALLED CRAZY HILL
IN GOODHUE COUNTY,
BROUGHT IT INTO OAKLAND
AND SOLD IT OUT OF THE HOUSE.AND THIS HAS TO DO
WITH COLIN HAYMER HOW?
APPARENTLY,
THEY ALSO SOLD DRUGS
THAT THEY BOUGHT
FROM BORDER CARTELS,
ANDTHEY PICKED UP SOME
OF THE CARTELS' HABITS
LIKE KIDNAPPING FOR CASH.
SO THEY WENT FROM DEALING POT
TO KIDNAPPING WEALTHY KIDS?
LESS EFFORT, MORE PROFIT.DO YOU HAVE ANY NAMES?
THEY'RE KNOWN AS
THE CRAZY HILL GANG.
ONE OF THE RINGLEADERS
WAS NICKNAMED "DEEZER."
NOBODY KNOWS HIS REAL NAME.
APPARENTLY,
DEEZER'S BEEN HANGING AROUND
AN APARTMENT BUILDING
IN WEST OAKLAND.
BOSS WANTS US TO CHECK
THE BUILDING OUT.FORGOT MY EXTRA MAGS.
MEET YOU DOWNSTAIRS.
[lowers voice] "EXTRA MAGS."
MM. BIG MAN.
WHERE'S YOUR VEST?
[normal voice]
DON'T NEED ONE.
SURE YOU DO.WE'RE JUST CANVASSING.
FOR PEOPLE CALLED
"THE CRAZY HILL GANG."
YOU SHOULD WEAR A VEST.
LOOK, IT'S HOT.
IT'S UNCOMFORTABLE.
HICKS ISN'T WEARING ONE.
[scoffs] WHAT, YOU'RE AFRAID
HE'LL MAKE FUN OF YOU?NO. NOT AT ALL.
[elevator bell dings,
doors open]DON'T BE AN IDIOT.
PUT ON A VEST.
FINE. GET SHOT.
SEE IF I CARE.
[speaks indistinctly]
THERE YOU GO.
ONE MORE?
SHE LIKES YOU.
SHE HAS GOOD TASTE.
YOU'RE GOOD WITH CHILDREN.UNLIKE YOUR EMPLOYERS?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU MEAN.OH, COME ON.
IT'S CLEAR TO SEE THEY'RE
SKITTISH ABOUT THE PARENTING.
I WOULDN'T KNOW
ANYTHING ABOUT THAT.
VERONA'S LOW SELF-ESTEEM
MAKES HER DOUBT
SHE'LL EVER BE A REAL PARENT.
AND BECAUSE DUNCAN
MARRIED HER FOR HER MONEY,
HE SEES THE CHILD
AS A RIVAL,
IN MORE THAN
THE USUAL FREUDIAN TERM.
THEY'RE VERY CARING PEOPLE,
VERY LOVING,
JUST NOT PARTICULARLY HANDS-ON,
IF YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN.
HOW'S DUNCAN'S RELATIONSHIP
WITH MIA?
IT CAN BE DIFFICULT.
WELL, IT MAKES SENSE.
IF HE SEES HIS CHILD AS A RIVAL,
WHY NOT HIS SISTER-IN-LAW?
I'VE HEARD ANGRY WORDS
BETWEEN THEM.
I THINK MIA
DOESN'T TRUST HIM.
BUT I SHOULDN'T SAY ANYTHING.
NO.
BUT YOU DID.
JANE,
WE GOT AN ERRAND TO RUN.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT.
[clears throat] GOTTA GO.
GOTTA GO AND RUN AN ERRAND
WITH THE BIG, SERIOUS MAN.COME ON. LET'S GO.
BYE.
SO WHAT'S THE DEAL HERE?
WELL, THE TATTOO
ON THE KIDNAPPER'S ARM
SUGGESTS THE, UH, MEXICAN MAFIA
MIGHT BE INVOLVED.MM-HMM.
THOSE GUYS--THEY'RE MEMBERS.
SO WE'RE GONNA GO TALK TO 'EM.
THEY LOOK SCARY.THEY ARE SCARY.
YOU CAN'T BECAUSE A FULL MEMBER
UNTIL YOU'VE KILLED SOMEONE.
MAYBE I'LL JUST WAIT
IN THE CAR.
NO. YOU'RE COMING WITH ME.
I NEED YOU FOR BACKUP.
BACKUP?
HEY, FELLAS.
HI. HOLA. ¿QúE PASó?
UM, LISTEN,
I'M AGENT, UH, BOSCO
WITH THE CBI.
AGENT JANE.HI.
I WAS WONDERING
IF ANY OF YOU FELLAS
HAVE SEEN YOUR MAN SNOOPY?
WE NEED TO TALK TO HIM.
SNOOPY?
SNOOP.
WE'RE LOOKIN' FOR HIM.
WE'D LIKE TO TALK TO HIM.
HEY, KEEP WALKIN', MAN.
WHO ARE YOU?
WHY ARE YOU BEING THAT WAY?
I ASKED YOU NICELY.
I-I ASKED--THE NAME IS RAOUL,
AND I AIN'T GOT NO WARRANTS,
SO BACK UP, FOOL.
WELL, RAOUL, YOU AND ME
ARE GONNA HAVE TO GO HAVE
A PRIVATE CHAT IN A MOMENT.NAH. I AIN'T DID NOTHING WRONG.
DON'T MAKE IT DIFFICULT.
TOUGH GUYS, HUH?
DEPENDS ON WHAT YOU MEAN
BY "TOUGH."
EMOTIONALLY RESILIENT?
YES.
SO NOW YOU
GONNA PLAY ME, TOO?
OH, RAOUL!COME ON!
THAT'S BATTERY
ON A STATE OFFICER.
NOW I'M GONNA
HAVE TO TAKE YOU IN.LOOK, I BARELY
TOUCHED HIM, HOMES!
YEAH? WE'RE GONNA GO HAVE
A CONVERSATION ABOUT RESPECT.[handcuffs click]
HOW ABOUT YOU?
COME ON. ANYBODY ELSE?[grunts]
YOU? YOU?ALL RIGHT.
I'M WAITING. MOVE!
THAT'S RIGHT, MOVE.THAT'S RIGHT. THANK YOU.
SO HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN
AN INFORMANT FOR THE CBI, RAOUL?
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT,
MAN? WHAT INFORMANT?
OH, COME ON.
YOU CAN COME CLEAN WITH ME.
WHO IS THIS GUY, SAM? HUH?
WHAT DID YOU TELL HIM?
WHAT'S GOING ON?EH. GUESS HE JUST
FIGURED IT OUT.
WELL, IT'S KIND OF OBVIOUS.
AS IF YOU'D WANT ME FOR BACKUP.
I MEAN, REALLY.
LISTEN, RAOUL, YOU KNOW ABOUT
THE WESTLAKE KIDNAPPING, RIGHT?
IS EMMEINVOLVED?
NO. I AIN'T HEARD
ANYTHING ABOUT THAT.
WESTLAKE?
YOU SURE?
SURE, NO, BUT WHEN
A BIG SCORE'S COMING UP,
I HEAR ABOUT IT.
PEOPLE START BRAGGING EVEN
BEFORE THEY GOT THE MONEY.
I AIN'T HEARD NOTHING
ABOUT THAT.
WELL, WE SAW EMMETATS
ON THE KIDNAPPERS.COME ON.
ANYBODY CAN GET A TATTOO.
YEAH, THEY WERE KIND OF SHOWY.
A LITTLE TOO VISIBLE,
DON'T YOU THINK?LIKE IT WAS MEANT
TO MISDIRECT US.
YOU KNOW, THAT KIND OF STUFF IS
GETTING TO BE A REAL PROBLEM--
PEOPLE PUTTING
THEIR CRIMES ON LA EMME.
SO YOU JACKED ME UP
FOR NOTHING.
WELL, THANKS A LOT.
UH, WE REALLY APPRECIATE IT.
UH, COME ON. GET IN.
AAH! ONLY NOW YOU GOTTA
PUNCH ME IN THE FACE.
MAY BE PEOPLE WATCHING.UH, YEAH, THEY'RE WATCHING.
[Bosco] OH, COME ON.SERIOUS. NEXT TIME YOU COME
AT ME IN THE STREET,
MAKE SURE IT'S FOR
A WORTHWHILE QUESTION. AAH!
OH. WHOO.[Raoul grunts]
THAT WAS GOOD. DID THAT HURT?
LOOKS LIKE IT HURT.
WATCH YOUR HEAD THERE.
[grunts]GET IN THERE.
[car engine starts]
[indistinct conversations]
HEY.
THANKS. THAT WAS FUN.
NO ACTUAL PROGRESS, BUT, UH,
CERTAINLY A LESSON IN LIFE
ON THE MEAN STREETS.
YEAH, WELL,
THAT'S WHAT COPS DO.
WE GET A LEAD,
WE RUN IT DOWN.
MOST LEADS DON'T WORK OUT.
WE MOVE ON.
BUT YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND THAT,
DO YOU?
ALL THIS KIND OF HARD,
METHODICAL WORK WE DO
IS SOMEHOW BENEATH YOU...
NOT YOUR SPEED.
OH, PLEASE,
GET OFF YOUR HORSE.
YOU JUST WANTED
TO FRIGHTEN ME AND IMPRESS ME
WITH YOUR MACHO COP PROWESS--
UNDERSTANDABLE IMPULSE.
A LITTLE JUVENILE, PERHAPS.
YOU SHOULDN'T BE
WORKING WITH US.
YOU'RE HURTING PEOPLE.
YOU KNOW THAT?
WHO?
THE COPS YOU WORK WITH.
DON'T KID YOURSELF.
THEIR CAREERS
ARE TAKING A HIT.
IF YOU CARE ABOUT 'EM,
YOU'LL LEAVE.
COPS I WORK WITH,
MEANING LISBON?AND HER TEAM.
BUT MOSTLY LISBON.
THAT RANSOM DEMAND--
DID SHE TALK TO YOU ABOUT THAT?
SURE.
AND YES, IT COULD MEAN
THERE'S SOMEONE ON THE INSIDE.
BECAUSE USEFUL TO KNOW
WHO IT IS, DON'T YOU THINK?
WELL, WE'RE WORKING THAT,
BUT THE RANSOM DROP'S
IN THREE HOURS.
WE MAKE A MOVE
ON A SUSPECT NOW,
ALL IT'LL DO IS
SPOOK THE KIDNAPPERS.
THEY'LL KILL MIA,
AND THEY'LL SCATTER.
WE GOTTA MAKE SURE
THE GIRL IS SAFE.SHE'S NOT GONNA BE SAFE.
THEY WILL KILL HER FIVE MINUTES
AFTER THEY GET THE RANSOM.COULD HAPPEN.
SO SHE DIES EITHER WAY.
WE COULD TRY SOMETHING.
NO.YOU WANT TO HEAR
WHAT I HAVE TO SAY?
NOT INTERESTED.
OKAY, SURE, ALL RIGHT.
WELL, I WAS VERY IMPRESSED,
BY THE WAY,
WITH THE MACHO COP PROWESS.
THOSE GUYS, THEY WERE
GENUINELY FRIGHTENED OF YOU.
YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY COOL, MAN.
YOU'RE GOOD OUT THERE.GO AWAY.
BULLITT.
LIKE, REALLY COOL.
KOJAK.
SORRY TO DISTURB YOU, MA'AM.
WE'RE LOOKING FOR AN INDIVIDUAL
BY THE NAME OF DEEZER--
MIGHT HAVE LIVED IN THE BUILDING
OR STAYED WITH SOMEONE HERE.NEVER HEARD OF HIM.
WHAT ABOUT THE CRAZY HILL GANG?
EVER HEARD OF THEM?NO.
WELL, IF YOU DO HEAR THEM,
YOU, UH, CALL US AT THIS NUMBER?
YOU WANT ME TO SPY
ON MY NEIGHBORS?
[whispers] FASCISTS.
[door slams]
MAKE A NEW FRIEND, BERT?
ENOUGH WITH THE "BERT,"
ALL RIGHT, HICKS?SORRY. HURT YOUR FEELINGS?
IT'S JUST NOT FUNNY,
THAT'S ALL.
IT'S A JOKE.
YOU CAN'T TAKE A JOKE?
EXCUSE ME, MA'AM,
I'M WITH THE CBI.
WONDERING IF I COULD ASK YOU
A FEW QUESTIONS.SURE, WHAT ABOUT?
I JUST THINK IT'S CHILDISH,
THAT'S ALL.AND I JUST THINK
YOU NEED TO LIGHTEN UP.
SORRY. NEVER HEARD OF HIM.
ALL RIGHT. THANKS ANYWAY.
YEAH?
WELL, MAYBE YOU NEED TO GROW UP.
IDIOT. UH, NOT... Y-YOU.
UM, WAYNE RIGSBY, CBI. NEED TO
ASK YOU A COUPLE OF QUESTIONS.
OH.
MA'AM, I WAS WONDERING IF I
COULD LEAVE A CARD WITH YOU.
GET IN! GO!
HICKS, COVER THE ROOM!
GO, GO!
[thud]
GRACE? GRACE![Van Pelt speaks indistinctly]
[clank]
GRACE!
WENT OUT THE WINDOW.I GOT IT. GO, GO, GO!
GRACE, YOU OKAY?
JUST BREATHE.
[grunting]I CAN'T SEE ANY BLOOD.
OHH. THE VEST TOOK IT. I'M OKAY.
I'M OKAY. GO, GO, GO, GO, GO.
GO. OKAY.[siren wailing]
[siren wailing]
[police radio chatter]
HOW YOU DOING?
THEY THINK A COUPLE ROUNDS
PROBABLY BROKE A COUPLE OF RIBS.
THEY'RE GONNA CHECK
FOR INTERNAL INJURIES.
I'M FINE. REALLY.
JUST MY LEGS KEEP TWITCHING.
THAT'S JUST ADRENALINE.
IT'LL WEAR OFF.
[lowers voice] DON'T EVER
DO THIS TO ME AGAIN.
NO PROBLEM.
GO INSIDE.
SEE IF THERE'S ANYTHING
IN THE SHOOTER'S APARTMENT
THAT TIES HER
TO THE KIDNAPPING.
OKAY.
YOU OKAY?
YEAH.
HEY, RIGSBY.
THANKS.
[creaks]
[whispers] HEY.
HEY.
MY LEG'S STILL TWITCHING.
I LOVE YOU.
THANKS.
I HAVE TO GO.
THEY DON'T EVEN KNOW I'M HERE.
I'LL CALL YOU LATER.WAYNE?
HUH?
ONE THING.
[slap]
WHAT WAS THAT FOR?
[voice breaking]
NEXT TIME WEAR YOUR VEST.
OKAY.
I MEAN IT.
YEAH. I BELIEVE YOU.
OHH. GET OUT OF HERE.
[door closes][whimpers]
[indistinct
police radio chatter]
IS SHE ALL RIGHT?YEAH.
THANK GOD.WELL, THANK KEVLAR, ACTUALLY.
HUSH. THIS IS OUR FAULT.
UH, WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
RIGSBY SAID THAT
HE AND HICKS WERE GOING AT IT
WHEN VAN PELT WAS SHOT.
THAT KIND OF BAD BLOOD
STARTS WITH US.SHE'S RIGHT.
THIS ISN'T ABOUT BAD BLOOD.
IT'S ABOUT PROFESSIONALISM.
THERE YOU GO AGAIN. YOU WON'T
TAKE ANY RESPONSIBILITY.
I.D. SAYS THE SHOOTER'S NAME
IS DIANE ZARANSKI.
YOU'RE KIDDING.NOPE. D.Z. DEEZER.
DIANE ZARANSKI WAS
COLIN HAYMER'S GIRLFRIEND.
S.F.P.D. SUSPECTED HER OF BEING
IN THE GANG THAT KIDNAPPED HIM.
THE CRAZY HILL GANG.
SAME CREW MUST HAVE
KIDNAPPED MIA WESTLAKE.WELL, NOW WE KNOW FOR SURE
THEY HAVE SOMEONE PLANTED
IN THE WESTLAKE HOUSE.
MM.THAT'S THE WAY THEY WORK.
WE'RE RUNNING BACKGROUND CHECKS
ON EVERYBODY THAT'S BEEN
INSIDE THAT HOUSE
IN THE PAST SIX MONTHS.YOU'RE NOT GONNA CATCH ANYONE
WITH A BACKGROUND CHECK.
THEY PLAN TOO CAREFULLY
FOR THAT.AND YOU DO KNOW
HOW TO CATCH HIM.
OF COURSE. I TOLD YOU I DO.FORGET IT.
YOU'RE NOT EVEN
GONNA HEAR HIM OUT?NO, HE'S GOT NOTHING
TO TELL ME.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
JANE'S NOT THE PROBLEM. YOU ARE.
YOU'RE SO STUCK ON THE IDEA
THAT HE'S NOT A COP
THAT YOU CAN'T SEE WHAT HE IS.
YOU KNOW HOW MANY CASES
HE'S CLOSED FOR US?
YOU THINK HE'S
GIVEN ME BAD HABITS?
I THINK HE'S MADE ME
A BETTER COP.THANK YOU, LISBON.
AND CAN I JUST ADD--
BE QUIET.I JUST--
IF YOU'RE SO SURE YOU'RE RIGHT
THAT YOU WON'T EVEN LISTEN
TO HIM, THEN YOU'RE
NOT A PERSON I KNOW.MM.
I DID HEAR YOU OUT,
AND I STILL SAY NO.
GOT THE MONEY
AND THE INSTRUCTIONS
FOR THE DROP-OFF.
HOW MUCH TIME?
ABOUT 20 MINUTES.[lowers voice]
YOU'RE MAKING A MISTAKE.
STOP IT.I'M JUST--
QUIET. MRS. WESTLAKE, I NEED
TO SPEAK TO YOU PRIVATELY.AGENT, I TOLD YOU--
I KNOW. COUNSELOR, I'M SORRY.
STAY HERE.
COME THIS WAY.
RIGHT IN HERE.
[grunts]
YOU ARE NOT WELCOME HERE,
JANE.
I'M GONNA TELL MINELLI
YOU REFUSED TO WORK WITH ME.OH, COME ON!
YOU CAN FACE HIM.
HOW DO YOU LIKE THAT?
YOU KNOW, YOU REALLY ARE
A SCHOOLBOY. YOU KNOW THAT?
JUST...
NOW WE'RE GONNA DO EXACTLY
AS THE KIDNAPPERS HAVE ASKED.
THAT IS THE BEST WAY
TO ENSURE THAT YOUR SISTER...
WILL COME HOME SAFELY.ABSURD.
BUT WE'RE GONNA DO ONE THING.
WE'RE GONNA PUT THIS SMALL
TRANSMITTER IN THE SUITCASE.OHH.
WHY?
IF THEY FAIL TO RETURN HER,
THIS IS THE BEST WAY
FOR US TO FOLLOW THEM.
WE'RE PRESUMING THEY'RE GONNA
TAKE THE MONEY
TO WHERE YOUR SISTER IS.IDIOCY.
WHAT WAS THAT, MR. JANE?THIS IS RIDICULOUS. YOU ARE
GONNA GET THAT GIRL KILLED.
STOP.EXCUSE ME, MA'AM.
THERE'S SOMETHING THAT
YOU REALLY SHOULD KNOW.KEEP TALKING.
I'M GONNA PUT MY HANDS ON YOU.
ONE OF THE KIDNAPPERS IS
IN THIS HOUSE RIGHT NOW.
DAMN IT.HERE?
A SPY, A MOLE,
REPORTING BACK TO THOSE
THAT ARE HOLDING YOUR SISTER.
WE SHOULD BE TALKING TO THEM,
NOT PLAYING WITH
"STAR WARS" TOYS.OH, MY GOD. WHO?
COME HERE.
[transmitter beeps]
HER.
YOU BITCH!
WHAT? JEEZ![man] WHAT--
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
YOU CRAZY BITCH![all shouting at once]
I'M GONNA KILL YOU![all shouting at once]
HOLD IT DOWN! NO, NO!
HOLD IT DOWN!
[Verona and Belinda shouting]
MY MONEY'S ON VERONA.
SANDBORNE'S GOT HER
ON EXPERIENCE,
BUT IT'S HARD TO BEAT
THAT KIND OF ENTHUSIASM.
WHOA.GOT THE IMAGE UP.
[Verona and Belinda
continuing shouting]
NOBODY.THERE WILL BE.
SOMEBODY BETTER COME.
IF NOBODY DOES,
YOU JUST KILLED MIA WESTLAKE.
BLAME, BLAME, BLAME, BLAME,
BLAME. SOMEBODY'S COMING.
DON'T WORRY.
AND THERE THEY ARE.
HELLO, MRS. KENT.
SHOULD WE GO GET HER?
NO. WAIT.
[starts engine]
MONEY'S ON ITS WAY.
IT'S CLEAN.
THEY TRIED PLANTING A TRACKER,
BUT I CAUGHT IT.
GET THE GIRL READY.[Lisbon]
HANDS WHERE I CAN SEE 'EM!
[Bosco] HANDS! HANDS!WHAT'S GOING ON?
DON'T MOVE. DON'T DO ANYTHING
UNLESS I TELL YOU TO.I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
THE BABY IS SLEEPING.
OH, THE BABY. SHE'S BEEN
WANDERING AROUND THE HOUSE
LIKE A LITTLE LOST LAMB.
YOU'RE JUST A TERRIBLE NANNY.
WHO WERE YOU TALKING TO
ON THE PHONE?
MY SISTER.IS SHE A KIDNAPPER, TOO?
NO!WHAT'S THIS?
LET ME GO.
LET US HAVE THE MONEY.
THE GIRL MIGHT LIVE.
PUT YOUR HANDS
BEHIND YOUR BACK.
YOU ARE MAKING
A BAD MISTAKE.
IF YOU PEOPLE
DON'T LET ME GO RIGHT NOW,
MIA WESTLAKE
WILL BE TORTURED TO DEATH
IF THEY THINK YOU'VE DONE
ANYTHING TO ME.
NO, THEY WON'T.
WE'RE GONNA GO GET HER.
GOOD LUCK FINDING HER.
WE DON'T NEED LUCK.
LET'S GO.
CHECKING...
LAST NUMBER CALLED.
767-555-0131.[typing on keyboard]
IT'S A LANDLINE.
[tapping keys]
1867 CLIFF POINT CIRCLE,
OAKLAND.
CALL OAKLAND P.D. TELL THEM
WE'RE TAKING THE HOUSE.
[explosions]
GET DOWN! DROP YOUR WEAPONS![man] GET DOWN!
[indistinct shouting, gunfire]
[Mia crying]MIA!
[both crying]
THOUGHT I WOULD RESURRECT
AN OLD TEQUILA TRADITION.
I'M IN.
CHEERS.
SMOOTH.
YES, IT IS.
[puts glass on table]
SO AM I SOMEONE
YOU KNOW NOW?
I'M STARTING
TO RECOGNIZE YOU, YEAH.
YOU KNOW THAT THING YOU SAID
ABOUT JANE MAKING YOU A BETTER
COP--YOU DON'T BELIEVE THAT.
I MAY HAVE EXAGGERATED
FOR EFFECT.
ANYWAY, I WANTED TO SAY
THAT IT'S BEEN NICE
WORKING WITH YOU AGAIN.
YOU, TOO.
ANYHOW...
GOOD NIGHT.
I'VE BEEN THINKING.
OH?
YOU'RE NOT A COP.
MNH-MNH.
YOU NEVER WILL BE.MNH-MNH.
BUT YOU HAVE A...
USEFUL PERSPECTIVE.
THIS IS A SUMMARY
OF THE RED JOHN CASE
SINCE I TOOK OVER.
TAKE A LOOK.
TELL ME WHAT YOU THINK.
BOSCO.
DON'T THANK ME.I WASN'T GOING TO.
I NEED THE ACTUAL CASE FILE--
UNABRIDGED.
YOU'RE A JERK.
YOU KNOW THAT?
NIGHT, BOSCO.
STAY TUNED FOR SCENES
FROM OUR NEXT EPISODE.